Everyone knows that you need a framework
for working with coding agents, but not
many people have one that's simple,
really their own, and something they can
evolve over time. Now, there are a lot
of over-engineered frameworks out there
on a GitHub. All these multi-agent
systems people are creating. I respect
what people are working on, but a lot of
times you just need something really
simple that just gets the job done for
you. Because I know that you have good
ideas that you want to build, and you
don't want to spend more time creating
your agentic coding workflows than you
do actually coding. And so, that's what
I have for you right now. This is my
dead simple framework that I use every
single time I'm starting a new project
with my coding agent. Now, brownfield
development, working on an existing
codebase, is slightly different. That's
for another video. This we're focusing
on greenfield development. We want a
simple framework to get our feet on the
ground running as fast as possible
building anything new. And everything
that I am covering here is universal.
These principles will apply no matter
the coding agent that you are using. So,
there are really two parts to this
video. And I'm going to be doing a live
build with you as I'm explaining
everything here to make it super
concrete. And so, what I have right now
with my codebase is pretty much nothing
besides my AI layer. So, there's a few
commands and skills that I brought over.
This is what I use as a starting point
for every single one of my projects.
We're going to be creating something
from scratch. And so, we need to start
with our initial planning, creating what
is called a PRD. This is the initial
scope of work that we have to create the
minimum viable product for our
application. And there's a lot that goes
here setting up our initial AI layer
before we get into any of the actual
coding. And then we take our PRD and we
split it up into phases of work. We're
going to knock it out with pivot loops.
And so, I'll talk about what that means.
We'll see an example of that. And then
while I'm going through this entire
implementation, I'll be covering the
four golden rules that we want to follow
all of the time. So, these golden rules
are going to fit in pretty naturally as
I'm going through creating the PRD, our
AI layer, and doing a piv loop. For
example, the context management. Context
is your most precious resource when
working with AI coding assistants.
That's going to be a big theme
throughout. Also, creating commands and
skills for everything and the system
evolution mindset because what we're
going for here with our system is to
create something that is reliable and
repeatable. And so, I'll be speaking to
that as I go through everything. So,
just trying to hit on some of the core
themes that you'll see throughout this.
It's going to be a very value-packed
video. And so, we'll start here with our
initial planning, creating what I like
to call the AI layer. So, I'll explain
what that is and we'll build it together
right now. So, your AI layer is all the
assets in your code base that you
created to be context for your coding
agent, like your PRD, what are we going
to build, your global rules, how are we
going to build it, the commands so we
have reusable workflows for our coding
agent. We'll focus on the prime one at
first, and then also sub agents so we
can delegate for research. And
generally, how I work with my AI layer,
and I have this as a resource for you,
is I have a more generic set of commands
that I'll bring into any new project.
And then, the point of this is as my
code base grows and I start to build it
out, I will also evolve my commands to
make them more powerful for the specific
use case, just making them more specific
to my code. And that's generally my
recommendation for you. And so, use this
as a starting point if you want. I'll
have a link to the GitHub repo in the
description. The point of keeping this
so simple is that you can take it for
yourself and easily evolve it for your
use case and how you like to work.
That's why I recommend something like
this over a more complex framework like
B mad or the GitHub specc kit. They're
really, really powerful, but it's hard
to really make it your own. I want you
to be able to make this your own. So,
right now, I'll show you what it looks
like to create an entire PRD, define the
initial rules for our code base. We'll
even customize our first command a
little bit, and then I'll talk about sub
agents throughout. And I know we're
doing a lot of planning before we write
any of our actual code with the Pivotal
use, but it's important to do this. And
doing the planning up front might seem
like we're taking things too slow, but
if we create a really good plan, like we
have good rules, a good PRD, it means
then all of our development after is
going to be a lot faster and more
reliable. So, let's start with our PRD.
A lot of people call this a spec. Again,
it's just the entire scope of work to
build out the initial version of our
application. And then after that point
when we have a good foundation, it moves
more to brownfield development. That's
the next video that I've got coming, so
stay tuned for that. And so, what I'll
do here with my Claude code, I got a
basically empty project here besides my
AI layer, is I will simply have a casual
conversation at first. Just telling it
about my idea, maybe some ideas I have
for the tech stack and the architecture.
You start really unstructured, which
also just makes it easy to get started,
and then you eventually get to the point
where you use your conversation as
context to create a structured PRD. And
I have a command that'll help us get the
job done. I'll cover that once we get
there. But first, let's just start with
our idea. And so, what I want to build
it just as a fun example for this video
is something kind of like Linktree, more
like a self-hosted version where you can
set up your own kind of landing page
that has a bunch of links that you can
organize. You have analytics like the
click-through rate on your different
links. I want to build something like
this. It's a good example for right now
because it's not super trivial where you
could just vibe code it really easily
with some of the more cool features we
can add in. But also, it's not going to
be overly complicated where we'll barely
have anything by the end of this video.
And so, I'm going to use a
speech-to-text tool to get the job done
here. I highly recommend using something
like AquaVoice. This is what I use.
There are a lot of good free and
open-source options as well.
WhisperFlow, Epicenter Whispering, great
tools that we have here. But love using
speech attacks cuz I can promise you I
will never be able to type 226 words per
minute. So, I use a tool like this just
to give a big brain dump at first for
what I want to build. And this is going
to be really raw, but I'm going to go
ahead and do a brain dump live for you
right now. And pay attention to what I
ask Claude code to do for me because
this is just as important as the ideas
that I'm sharing. I'll explain a little
bit about that after as well. And by the
way, you can do this entire thing with
any AI coding assistant. So, here we go.
I want to build a link in bio page
builder. So, something kind of like
Linktree. Users can create an account,
they can create their own landing page
where they specify the links, they can
change the order. I want them to be able
to have analytics so so they can view
the click-through rates on their links
as well and they can customize the
theme. And then for the tech stack, I'm
thinking probably like Next.js. I'd like
to use Neon for my database and Neon
authentication. So, definitely spin up a
sub agent to do some research for that.
Uh and then for the architecture, not
super picky on that. Definitely want
your recommendations for that and just
how we're going to handle the theming
and the link building, all of that. And
so, I want you to also spin off an agent
to do a bunch of web research on just
like best practices for creating these
Linktree type applications. And then
what I want you to do after is come back
to me with a bunch of questions so we
can get on the same page with even the
little details for what we are building
here. All right, very good. So, I'm
going to go ahead and send that off and
it'll just transcribe it a couple of
seconds here. There we go and boom, we
are off to the races. And the most
important thing that I did there is
actually right at the end when I told it
to ask me a bunch of questions after it
does its research. So, this is really
important to drive home here. Your
number one goal for any kind of planning
with coding agents is to reduce the
number of assumptions that your coding
agent is making. Cuz in the end, when
When agent makes a mistake in your code
base, half the time it's not that the
code is bad, it's that you just weren't
aligned on what exactly you should be
building. The common adage is that one
line of bad code is just one line of bad
code. One line of a bad plan is maybe a
hundred lines of bad code. But then one
bad line in a PRD, that could be a
thousand bad lines of code because you
have misalignment. And so, I have been
doing a lot of experimentation with ways
to, you know, reduce assumptions over
time. And having the coding agent
actually just give me a flurry of
questions has worked so incredibly well
for me because, especially Claude Code
with its ask user question tool, where
it can give like multiple choice or
write your own answer, we'll see that in
a second. It's so powerful. Like they do
a really good job thinking about all the
edge cases and little details that maybe
we aren't even thinking about. Like it's
hard for us to just reason ourselves
about what assumptions the coding agent
might make, so it's very, very powerful.
And then the other thing that I did, as
you can see right here, is we have
different sub agents that are running
for research. I love using sub agents
for any kind of planning, creating the
PRD, or even for the planning process of
the pivot loops that we'll talk about in
a little bit. And so with Claude Code, I
don't actually have to create my own sub
agents because we have the exploration
and research sub agents built right into
the tool. For other coding agents, you
might have to build your own, which is
why I wanted to call it out here. But
pretty much every single good coding
agent these days supports the idea of
sub agents. I love using them for
research. And the reason for that is
context isolation. Again, one of the key
themes here is we want to really protect
the context of our main coding agent.
And the reason that research is such a
good use case for sub agents
specifically is because when they
explore, they're looking at everything.
They're doing a bunch of code base
exploration or web research. They're
loading in tens, even hundreds of
thousands of tokens for their work, but
really all we care about is their
findings, the summary at the end that
they return to our main context. And so
we can keep our main context clean. I
don't recommend using sub-agents for
implementation, because with
implementation we usually care about all
of the context of the files that we've
been editing and creating. Otherwise, it
leads to a lot of hallucinations in my
experience. And that's also why Claude
Code doesn't have any built-in agents
for implementation, it's just for
research. And that's exactly what we are
seeing right here. And so I'm going to
let everything complete, and then I'll
come back once it has the questions for
us. All right, so all of our sub-agent
research is done, and we now have the
initial set of questions to answer. And
as I go through this, I think you'll
really appreciate as much as I do,
because we are clarifying a ton of
things. Every single question that we
answer here is removing an assumption
from the coding agent. And because it's
multiple choice, and usually one of the
options it presents here is good, we can
blitz through this really quickly. And
so we can be pretty confident going into
the implementation that we have all of
the details locked down. And so for
example, how should the public page URL
structure work? I actually like option
number one here, and then boom, onto the
next one. How many pages should each
user be able to create? Let's just do
one page per user. I mean, some of these
I'm just going to keep going with the
defaults here, but there are a lot of
instances where it really fundamentally
misunderstands something, and that's
where I can type my own answer to really
clarify. So I don't know if I'll run
into an example right here, but what I'm
going to do is I'm just going to go
through and answer all of its questions,
come back once I've done that. You don't
really need to see me do every single
question here, cuz it might do up to
like 20, 25 questions. Like it will take
this pretty far. And so again, you have
to be a bit patient with this, but every
single question you answer could save
you from having hundreds of lines of bad
code. So actually, here is a good
example where I want to clarify
something entirely different from what
it suggested here. So it's saying this
is the second batch of questions that
Claude has asked me, by the way. Should
the link editor have a live phone frame
preview? So, kind of like lovable or
bold on new, where you have the the view
of what you're creating and then you
have the builder on the left side, or
should it be inline? And I kind of want
to actually have both options here. So,
I can go to the chat about this. And so,
then it will ask me other questions
after, but now we get to have a little
bit of a conversation for this thing
specifically. And so, I'll say right
here, "I want to have an inline editor,
but I want the option to be able to see
the preview as well. So, essentially, I
want to have three buttons. One where I
just see the editor, one where I see
both, and then one where I just see the
preview." So, I send that in and then
it'll come back and ask me more
questions and I'll just continue the
process. So, here we are. Claude
finished asking me a bunch of questions,
probably more than I need, but you can
really just tweak this to whatever you
want to do. And now it's time to create
our PRD, because as we can see from the
final spec summary, it really [snorts]
does have a clear understanding of
exactly what we're going to build, even
where I'm going to deploy it. I'm going
to deploy this to Vercel after I build
it. This is fantastic. Like, I feel like
it isn't really assuming much anymore.
So, now what I'm going to do is just run
my create PRD command. I'll just put
this in .claude/prd.md.
You can really put this wherever you
want. You can even call it whatever you
want. And so, I am using the command
that I mentioned earlier. Because going
back to our four golden rules, one of
the big ones here is to commandify
everything. If you do something more
than twice, which I have been definitely
started more than a couple of projects,
you should make it a command. And then,
otherwise known as skill, because Claude
Code did recently merge commands with
skills, but I still like to have the
distinction of commands are things that
you invoke yourself, like
commit. And then, skills, that's when an
agent decides to read context, like
understanding how to do something new.
And so, I'm creating a command here
because I'm designing, okay, at this
point in the conversation, I want to run
this command to output a structured PRD.
So, as a part of this command, I'm
giving it the exact structure, all the
different sections that I want in the
PRD. So, that way I'm making my whole
process repeatable, right? A big part of
this system that I'm showing you here is
you can create something that works for
you, and then you can do it over and
over and over again for new features and
new code bases. And so, I'm going to do
a slash create PRD. I'm going to let it
rip, and I'll come back once we have our
final PRD. All right, so our PRD is now
created, and it is very comprehensive,
but that's good because it's not like
we're going to send this into our coding
agent to implement. Instead, we're going
to build things in phases that are
described by our PRD. So, I'm not going
to do a ton of validation on camera
right now. Definitely not worth your
time, but I do want to say that it is
important to read through this and make
sure that you really are aligned on
everything. Otherwise, it is going to
lead to a lot of bad code in the future.
And so, the first thing I want to call
out really quick here is we have our MVP
scope, and in this, we can see all of
our questions coming to life in our PRD,
and that's important because the
conversation we just had was really just
unstructured context to feed into the
PRD. The PRD is the only thing that's
going to survive, so we need to make
sure that the entire conversation that
we have with our agent is really put in
here. We have our out of scope, which is
equally as important, what we don't want
to build right now. We have the entire
directory structure, so it already
understands generally what is going to
go into our code base, which is good
because we've already established our
tech stack and architecture.
And the important thing with this is
that we have our phases of work. And so,
from this, when we use our prime command
that I'll talk about in a little bit,
we're able to establish like, okay, what
have we already built in our code base?
What do we have to build next based on
the PRD? So, this is going to be one of
the important pieces of context at the
start of every conversation as we build
our MVP. And by the way, here's the
section itself where I lay out the
phases. Each one of these is going to be
a granular implementation one of our Piv
loose. So, we build the foundation, then
we build the link management, then we do
the theme. We're going to plan each one
of these individually, so we're not
trying to have the coding agent ever do
too much at once. Okay, so we just
created our PRD, and that really is the
biggest thing. So, we're almost there
getting to our first implementation. The
next thing that we have to set up is our
rules. And this is going to be pretty
basic at first because our rules are
definitely going to evolve the most as
we are evolving our actual code base.
And so, I'm using Claude code. I'm just
referring to agents and agents.md cuz
this is more of the universal standard
for the naming for global rules. And so,
the important thing here is that the
constraints and conventions that we
always want our coding agent to follow,
this goes in our global rule file. And
so, this is things like the commands to
run our application, our testing
strategy, our logging strategy. No
matter what we're building, we always
want our coding agent to see this. And
so, we want to create this right now, at
least an initial version to get us
started. And then the other component I
have here is the reference folder. You
can also use Claude code skills for
this, by the way, but this is just more
universal cuz a lot of times we have
other contexts we want the agent to have
in mind, but only when we're working on
specific parts of our application, like
a guide to building front-end components
if we're working on the front end. And
the reason we don't want to just dump
this all into our agents.md is this is
loaded into the context of the coding
agent every single conversation. And
remember, context is precious, so we
want to keep this really concise, and
then just point it to each of these
files. So, we can tell the coding agent,
"If you are working on the front end,
then you can read this file." Or if
you're building new API endpoints, "Then
you can read this file." So, this is
essentially progressive disclosure. We
have different layers of context that
the agent can discover over time to make
sure it's only loading what it actually
needs based on the the task at hand. And
so, for this one, I have yet another
command. Again, commandify everything.
Just like I have a template I like for
my PRDs, I have a template that I like
for creating my global rules. And so,
first, we are going to discover what we
already have in the code base, cuz I
created this to work for existing code
bases and new ones. And so, for this,
really all it's going to explore is the
PRD. It's going to figure out what's our
tech stack, what's our architecture, do
some web research for testing and
logging strategies, and then bring all
that together with my guide to create my
global rules. And I have the exact
structure here. And so, it's going to be
based off of this template that I have.
So, I'll show you this very quickly as
well, because this is the template that
I love using for all of my global rules.
And you can see that everything here we
really do care about our agency no
matter what. Like, okay, here's our tech
stack, the commands to run in testings,
our project structure, so it has
essentially an index of our code base,
our architecture, our code patterns,
like things like naming conventions,
testing and validation strategies. It's
pretty basic overall. But, we're going
to create this first, and then I'll give
you a couple of examples of reference
documents, like our secondary on-demand
context. And so, I'll go into Claude
here, and really just in the same
conversation where I created my PRD, I'm
just going to do create rules, because I
can really use all of this conversation
as context to help so it just right away
it knows, okay, here's our PRD, here's
our tech stack and things like that. All
right, so our create rules command
finished, and we now have our global
rules. And so, I have it pulled up
already. Pretty standard here. We have
our tech stack, the commands, like we're
using Drizzle ORM for our database, for
example, project structure,
architecture, code patterns. For the
sake of brevity, I'm not really
customizing things here or applying my
own thoughts to this very much, but
depending on how technical you are, this
is your time to make sure that the
constraints and conventions, the code
patterns is really aligned with how you
want to create your code bases. So, you
can spend a lot of time with this if you
want. I'm just not doing it because I'm
focusing on the high-level ideas with
you right here. And so I also had to do
some web research on best practices for
creating things like front-end
components and API endpoints. And then
based on that, I had to create some
on-demand context as well. And again,
these could be cloud code skills if you
would like. And so if we go back to the
global rules, let me scroll down to the
on-demand context section. Here we go.
When working on front-end components,
read this file. When working on API
routes, read this file. So the claw.md
is the only thing loaded in up front,
but then it'll decide to bring this in
when it needs. And in my experience,
it's really good at referencing this,
especially if our global rules is
concise like it should be. Like we don't
even have 240 lines here. Just 233 lines
for our global rules. And then we have
our API.md and components.md. These are
a lot bigger because when we are working
on the task and it's very specific to
this, then it's okay to bring in a lot
more information to make sure we have
good guidance for our coding agent. So
again, going back to our diagram here,
the rules, this is how we want to build
things. The PRD is what exactly we're
going to build. And so with both of
these things in mind, the last thing
that I want to talk about here is
commands, specifically the prime
command. Then we'll get into building
the plan for our first phase and
creating the code. So at this point, we
have the initial AI layer. We have our
PRD, our rules, and those generic
commands that I brought in that you can
feel free to use for yourself. And so
we're going on to implementation now.
But here's the thing. At the start of
every new conversation with an AI coding
assistant, we need it to catch itself up
to speed on the code base. What are we
building? What comes next? That is where
the prime command comes in. And so this
is a command we'll run  prime at
the start of every new session. It is a
guided process for it to explore our
code base and get itself to the point
where it has a mental model where it's
ready for the next feature
implementation. And so we'll have it
read documentation, explore the
structure. It can use sub agents to do
all this as well, checking the Git log,
cuz that's another thing that I'll talk
about more in a bit as well, is using
Git log as our long-term memory. So it
can see over time how our code base has
been evolving because that'll help it
make decisions around what it's going to
build next. And so after this command,
it's going to output to us its
understanding of the code base, so we
can validate it knows what's up with our
code base, and we can go on to building
the next thing. And so not to cover the
prime command in too much detail right
here, but we do some operations with Git
to take advantage of the history, and
then we're reading through the core
files and identifying anything that we
need to pay special attention to that
are like main entry points to our
application, for example. And then this
output report is how we can validate its
understanding. And that we can evolve
this over time to make it specific to
our project. Just to give you one really
small example here, for reading core
documentation, I could say read the
Drizzle migrations so you understand the
database schema, right? It even had the
tab complete there, it knew exactly what
I was going for. And so as you kind of
build your own understanding of like
what are the core things I want my
coding agent to pay attention to in this
code base, like maybe other
documentation we have in the reference
folder, for example, we can add that
here. And so now what I'll do is I'll go
into Claude, but I'm going to start a
brand new conversation because now we're
going to get into our first PIV loop,
and I'll explain the entire PIV loop in
a little bit here. But watch this, I'm
just going to run prime, and that's
going to be the beginning of my
conversation. Before I do anything, I
want to explore. And so in this case,
it's going to realize like, okay, this
is a brand new project. Let me check the
PRD, and it's going to recommend like,
let's do phase one first. Let's create
the foundation for our project. So our
prime completed, here is the project
overview, a link in bio page builder.
The current state, it's an empty
repository with a just documentation. I
did do a test build earlier, which is
why it says this, but I cleared
everything for right now.
And then it pulled the first phase, the
foundation, from our PRD. And this is
what it's recommending that we build,
and that's exactly what I am going for
here. I want it to pick out phases one
at a time from the PRD, so we have
granular implementations for our piv
loops. Which, speaking of the piv loops,
we are going to get into this now. And
so, piv is short for plan, implement,
validate. We take focused work, usually
a phase from a PRD, and we run it
through this entire process. So, we
create a structured plan, that's this
part right here, around what we're going
to tackle. And this process is actually
pretty similar to creating a PRD. Then
we go into the implementation, and our
goal here is to delegate all coding to
the coding agent. And then we do the
validation after.
And so, I'm going to cover really
quickly what this process looks like,
then we're going to go through it in
action. And so, first of all, when we
are in our planning, we have two layers
of planning. We have the top-level
project planning. That is what we
already did, creating our PRD and our
rules. And now we have the task-specific
planning. So, like I just mentioned,
these are pretty similar. Creating a
structured plan is pretty similar to
creating our structured PRD. The main
difference is the structured plan is
just very focused on an individual
feature and all of the tasks that come
with that. So, now we're getting down to
the code, we're not as high-level. But,
we are still going to start with a very
unstructured conversation. I like to
call it vibe planning. We're just going
to explore general ideas, what's the
architecture for what we're building
specifically, spinning off sub-agents
for code base analysis and
documentation.
And then just figuring out like what are
the specific tasks that we need to knock
out for this feature. And so, we have
this conversation, I'll show you an
example of this, and then we turn that
into a structured document, just like
with the PRD. So, the goal here is to
create a detailed plan of attack for the
AI coding assistant based on our
conversation. So, the conversation is a
part of our context. But, here we have
very specific sections that I want to
create in the structure plan. The goal
and success criteria of this feature,
any documentation that we want to
reference that maybe one of the sub
agents found, our task list which can be
as specific as even the individual files
that we want to create and update. And
then probably the most important part
out of this entire plan is the
validation strategy. This is kind of
like test-driven development where we
want to be very specific with how we can
validate the feature before we even
write a single line of code. This forces
both us and the coding agent to be very
specific about the success criteria.
And so, we create our structure plan and
we are very much a part of this. But,
then we delegate all of the coding to
the agent itself. This is not vibe
coding, though. The only reason that I'm
going to trust the agent, but verify, is
because I am sandwiching the
implementation with the planning and the
validation that I am very much a part of
the process for. And so, we are going to
have the coding agent check its own work
with unit testing and integration
testing and end-to-end testing. We'll
see that as well. But, then I am going
to run my own code review and manually
test the application. I'll spin it up
myself. I'll go through the application
just like a user would. Make sure that
everything is working good before I make
that commit and send it off to
production or staging or whatever.
The important thing here is that in
between the planning and the
implementation, I am going to be
resetting the context. This is one of
the golden rules. Context is very
precious. And so, I have a long and
detailed conversation figuring out this
feature we're going to implement. And
then the structured plan that I create
right here, I want it to be all of the
context the coding agent needs to get
the job done so that I can have a fresh
conversation where the plan is the only
thing I send in because it has all the
documentation to reference. It has the
entire task list, so we know what we
have to do. We know how to validate, so
that way we can just cut things off and
go into execution to keep things very
focused, right? We want to not have a
bunch of context bloating the
conversation when we get into writing
the actual code. All right, so with
that, let's now get into our first pivot
loop. And this is going to be a lot
simpler than you would think because we
really are going to reap the rewards
from all of the planning that we did up
front. We are on the same page with our
coding agent. We're confident
understands what we want to build. And
so there's not even that much planning
we're going to have to do for each of
these phases, at least at first. And so
going back here, we have finished the
prime. We are on the same page with the
coding agent. And I just gave it a
really simple prompt here. Like, "Yeah,
phase one looks good. Just confirm to me
exactly everything that we're going to
build." Now usually for pivot loops
after the first one, it's a bit more
detailed. Like, "Let's look at the code
base and figure out how exactly we're
going to build this." But right here
it's really simple. So this looks good.
And now remember, commandify everything.
I want to turn this conversation and
this idea of phase one into a structured
plan with a task list and validation. So
I have another command for that. It is
just called create or plan feature
plan feature. There we go. So
I'll send this in. And now a plan
feature, just like the create PRD, it
has this idea of a structured plan built
in. So I'll show you this command as
well.
So plan feature, open this up. So it
accepts an optional argument where I can
specify what I want to build. In this
case, I'm just using the conversation
history, so it already knew. But we go
through a phased process here. So
feature understanding, diving into the
code base, which is again more
applicable for future pivot loops. But
it does a lot of research, pulling
relevant documentation, making sure we
have a a rich set of context going into
the execution. And then what you're
looking at here, this is the template.
So we want to describe the problem
statement, any context or reference. We
have our implementation plan
with the task list right here. And then,
of course, we have our testing strategy.
We want to define the validation up
front. And after we create this plan, of
course, we're going to validate it.
We're going to make sure that we're very
specific, the step-by-step, here's
exactly how we want you to validate the
application. And I am actually using the
Vercel Agent Browser CLI skill, which I
made a video on that I'll link to right
here. So, we're going to build in full
browser automation. The agent is going
to spin up the back end and front end,
run the database migrations, go through
and like build its own Linktree, and
basically just make sure everything is
working exactly how a user would use the
application. So, pretty exciting. The
validation is going to be very detailed
here, so that by the time control is
passed back to us, we can be very
confident in the implementation. Still
doing validation ourself, but it's going
to be a lot less work. Okay, and our
plan is created now. So, let's go ahead
and take a look. So, I did a bit of
validation off camera. I'll show you
that in a little bit. Usually, you will
iterate a good amount because you want
to make sure that its understanding of
phase one is aligned with what you have
in the PRD, what you actually want to
build. Go through all of the sections. I
encourage you to do so. So, here's our
implementation plan with the task list.
It's very detailed, which is good. You
want to be specific now that we are very
focused on a single feature. We have our
validation with the whole validation
pyramid, as I like to call it. So, type
checking and linting and unit testing.
And then, we're very specific for the
end-to-end testing, all the user
journeys you want the agent to go
through, so we can be confident in the
implementation when it comes back to us.
And that's something it didn't really do
that well at first. And so, I did have a
follow-up prompt here, just to give you
a quick example of how we can iterate
and refine the plan before we send it
off to implementation. And then, one
other little golden nugget. I promise
we'll get into implementation in a sec,
but this is really important. Uh
generally, coding agents aren't the best
at working with environment variables.
They'll get tripped up. If you don't
have the environment variables set
before implementation, it'll just do a
bunch of mock testing and say
everything's validated when it isn't
actually. It's really frustrating. And
so, usually what I like to do in
parallel with the planning is that we'll
create a .env.example
and I'll have it look here, so it knows
all the environment variables that I
have set, and then I will set up my
environment variables as well. So,
obviously, I won't show this file cuz it
has my secrets for the database URL and
things like that. But, because I already
have that set up, now we can rip through
the entire implementation and then not
just write the code, but it can run the
database migration, start up the back
end and front end, use the Vercel agent
browser CLI to test everything, and it
doesn't have to get interrupted for me
to set my environment variables. And so,
I have the stage set up perfectly now
going into implementation, and I'm
pretty happy with this plan. So now,
remember, context reset because context
is precious. I am now in a brand new
context window where I will use my
execute command, and the one parameter
is the plan that I'm pointing it to.
This is all it needs for its context
now.
And so, what I'll do is I'll pause and
come back once it's gone through the
entire thing. And really, we are
delegating all the coding to the agent
now, reaping the rewards of all the
effort we put into planning. Every
single pivot loop after this point is
going to be so fast now because of the
work that we put into this. All right,
our implementation is complete. We can
see from the screenshots full end-to-end
so we can be pretty confident in the
implementation because the agent already
took care of everything right here, but
it's still important for us to do the
human validation so we can really make
sure that we are trusting but verifying.
And so, the code review, that gets
pretty in the weeds, so I'm not going to
do this right now, but if you're more
technical, it's definitely important
that you do so. But, what I am going to
do is test the application live with
you. So, the only thing I did off camera
is I created an account already, just to
make sure that the basic authentication
is working, but I haven't done anything
here yet. And take a look at this. This
is so cool. It already looks really,
really nice. So, I can set my display
name. I can do a bio, like a cool AI
builder. All right, I can set my avatar
URL. So, I just uploaded a image to
Imgur. So, okay, that's looking really
nice as well. I can add some links, like
okay, I'll do YouTube, and then that's
https uh youtube.com/
@colmedina. All right, looking nice. Add
another link, I'll do LinkedIn. I don't
have my LinkedIn URL right now, so I'll
just do like linkedin.com. Don't really
care. All right, cool. And let me just
add one more, I'll do X. All right, so
uh let's just do x.com. Very cool. And I
can drag these around to reorder them.
It's automatically reflected here. I can
view just the editor, and then adjust
the preview. The theme doesn't look the
best right now, like it's just white,
but I think that comes in a later phase
anyway, cuz right now we are just
building the foundation. So, a lot of
this isn't perfect yet, but it's still
looking extremely good for a starting
point. And then I can click save. And um
okay, yeah, it has to load the API
endpoints since we're running this
localhost. There we go, changes saved
successfully. So, I can do a refresh,
and everything is still going to be
there. All right, that's amazing. So,
this is looking really, really good.
Now, what I want to talk about, since
we've gotten to a good foundation built,
is the commit message, just really
quickly here. And so, I have another
command called /commit. And this one's
really, really basic. You can make this
more detailed if you want, but
essentially, you just want to provide
instructions to the agent for how to
create a Git message, because we are
going to use that as our long-term
memory. So, going back to the diagram
here, this is one of those golden rules.
Your commit history is your long-term
memory. So, if we are standardizing our
message, and that's why we're using a
command, /commit, to make this reusable,
then our agent, when it's going through
the prime, it can look at the Git log to
see a history of what we've built
recently, which will guide what comes
next, and maybe patterns that we want it
to follow. And so that's the power of
this commit message right here. So I'll
do  commit, which I could just
run get commit myself. It's really,
really easy, but this just makes it so
it's always the same kind of message for
consistency. So in this case, there's
nothing to commit cuz I already ran this
off camera as well, but that is
important to take care of after every
single implementation. Now, one other
super important thing to cover after we
have the foundation of our project laid
out, is you want to set up a framework
for regression testing. We want to make
sure that as we go through future pivot
loops, so we go through this process
over and over again for all the features
we want to build, we need to make sure
the old stuff doesn't break. And so this
I'm going to cover more in a different
video, all the strategies that I have
for implementing this sort of testing
harness yourself. Cuz essentially, you
go into the agent and say like, "Okay,
what we have now is great, but I can
also go into AquaVoice here and say,
I want you to list out all of the
end-to-end testing that you did. Put
this into a command for me so I can run
this later after I've built other
features so that we can make sure that
everything that we built previously is
still working." Right? Something kind of
like that. Again, I'm not going to get
too in the weeds of this right now. It
takes a while to set this up and kind of
create a test harness, but this is how
you make sure that your application is
stable as you're continuing to build on
top of it. And it does take a lot of
work to create and maintain this cuz you
constantly have to update it. And so
there are also solutions out there that
take care of this for you and they are
very powerful. And one of these
applications is QA Tech. They have AI
testing agents that evolve. They adapt
with your code base. So as you're adding
more and more features, they add more
and more test cases to make sure that
everything your application is working
well as you're continuing to build it
out. And so I'll show you an example of
this really quickly. It's so easy to get
started. So you go into QA Tech, they
got a free tier for you to get started
and try this out. I'll create a project
here and then you just have to paste in
a URL that you want to test. And so I
took this application since I already
made a commit and push it to GitHub, I
deployed it in just like a minute to
Vercel. So the easiest place to host
your sites for free, especially when you
build with Next.js. And so I'm going to
go to my project here and just paste in
this URL. And so it'll take a little bit
to create your project and analyze your
code base. And what we can do is just
say I want a good test set up for my
site. create the first three to five
test cases. And this is kind of like,
you know, Bolt.new or Lovable where you
can just give a prompt for whatever you
want it to do to set up the test suite
for your project. But this is what they
recommend to get started. So I'm going
to go ahead and send this in. And it's
so cool because it will dig through your
website, like actually crawl through it.
But you don't have to manage the
infrastructure at all. So it analyzes
your website and comes up with the test
cases. And so I'll come back once it has
done that. So mid-execution, just want
to show you really quick that it crawled
my website in just a couple of minutes.
And then one of the really important
things is we need a way to log into our
website. We want the automation to be
able to do that. And so they have a way
for us to enter in our username and
password and then they're going to store
it in a secure way. So I just have a
test account created here. Going to go
ahead and save that. And then it'll use
that to get into the website, really dig
in and understand all of the user
journeys that we want to test here. And
there we go. It has generated a bunch of
test cases for us. And we can even click
into each one of these. And we can see
the exact flow that it went through. And
so now we have all these tests that are
set up. And the AI testing agents in QA
Tech are going to evolve these test
cases over time to make sure it
continues to cover everything in our
code base as we build more and more
features. It is super, super cool. And
again, we can build our own kind of
command system to do something like
this, but I really appreciate having a
platform that just takes care of all of
this for me. And there's agents under
the hood that I can chat with to even
just like work with the testing here and
make sure that I am truly regression
testing everything. And so then whenever
there's anything that breaks, I can come
in here and say like, "Hey, there's a
bug with the application right now.
Create a test that should be failing.
Let me address the problem, and then the
test should be passing."
And so that takes us to the last golden
rule that I have here, the system
evolution mindset. So whenever we
encounter a bug in our code base, it is
important to not just address the bug,
but think about what we can fix in our
AI layer so it doesn't happen again.
Like maybe we need to be more specific
about our style guide and our rules, or
create a new on-demand context for that.
Maybe we need to have more end-to-end
testing that's laid out in our commands,
our workflows, whatever it takes to make
sure that we don't encounter this issue
again. And then we can also do what I
just showed in QA Tech or our own
command system, where we add a test to
make sure that we don't encounter that
issue again in the code base. And so the
power of this, even though it takes time
to do it, is that we make our coding
agent more reliable and repeatable over
time, evolving it along with our code
base. And so we're doing three things in
parallel. As we're building out our code
base, we are evolving our test base, our
code base, and our AI layer. And man,
does that compound over time. And so
going back to Claude code here, I'll
just give you a really simple example of
this. So one thing that I did do to
iterate once off camera is I worked on
the style for the site. Cuz if you go
back to the start of the video, you'll
see that I kind of forgot to talk about
the style, exactly how I wanted the site
to look. So Claude code just kind of
made its own assumptions there. And they
didn't look the best, and so I had to
iterate on that. And so one thing that I
can do here is
you know what, first I didn't like the
style that you implemented for the front
end. We definitely don't have enough in
the AI layer with our rules and
on-demand context for a style guideline.
So I want you to do some meta reasoning
here. Don't change anything, but help me
think about right now. What could we
change with our rules or on-demand
context, something we could add or
update, so that we have a more
consistent styles that we're going to be
building as we continue to, you know,
build up the analytics and other things
other pages in this application.
And so, the important thing I'm doing
here is telling it to not change
anything yet because usually I want to
have a lot more control over changing
the AI layer versus for the code base, I
just want to delegate as much of that to
the agent as possible. So, I have it
reason with me, but I usually like to
make these small and very focused
changes myself. And you can see here
that it recommends creating a style.md
in the reference folder. So, a third
piece of on-demand context for us. And
so, this I guess would go along with the
components.md. That's more like here's
how we should layout things. And then
the styles.md is here's how it works.
Here's how we should work with Tailwind
CSS and probably shadcn for example. So,
I'm not going to go through the full
implementation of this and correcting
everything, but just trying to give you
a good example here of how when we
encounter anything where we have bugs in
the code or just isn't quite aligned
with us like we have right here, it's
always an opportunity for us to evolve
the AI layer. So, we're more and more in
tune with our coding agent for this
specific project as we continue to build
it out. And that, my friend, is the most
high leverage part of the entire
process. Really saving the best for the
end. So, that is everything. It really
is a dead simple process for getting
reliable and repeatable results with
your coding agents when you are starting
new projects because now after the
system evolution, we just take it back
up to the top and we go through more
pivot loops going through the exact same
process to build out all the phases in
our PRD, add any other features,
whatever it takes to get to that minimum
product. And then that'll take us into
brownfield development with one of the
next videos that I'll put out on my
channel. And so, if this all sounds good
to you and you want to dive even deeper
with my full resource library of
commands and rules, you want to see what
system evolution really looks like and
get deep into that, definitely check out
the agentic coding course that I have in
the Dynamis community. I'll have a link
to this in the description and the
pinned comment. And so, that's
everything that I got for you right now.
So, if you appreciated this video,
you're looking forward to more things on
agent coding, that brownfield
development video, I'd really appreciate
a like and a subscribe. And with that, I
will see you in the next video.